SUPRESH MAHAJAN

6005536576 • msupresh31@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/supresh-mahajan-a35026173

Summary

An IT Professional with 2+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Successfully led a team of 3 deriving productivity and good results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Stonewain Systems Inc

Chandigarh

Software Development Engineer

07/2022 - Present

- Implemented a new microservice to store static data of 70+ tables in caches.
- Successfully upgraded whole project from Java 8 to 11.
- Enhanced CI/CD pipeline with **Python** scripts, **Maven**, and **Jenkins**; cut deployment time by 35% and decreased manual intervention by 50%, leading to more reliable and faster releases.
- Incorporated centralized config server backed up by Gerrit to improve CI/CD pipeline.
- Trained a team of 3 members and led the team to automate the manual deployment and report generation processes.
- Created a Rule Engine in the Spring Boot application to apply more than 100 set of rules stated by the user

Stonewain Systems Inc

Chandigarh

Software Development Intern

01/2022 - 06/2022

- Added bulk booking via Rest API calls in the application using concepts of Spring AOP and Completable Future which improved performance by 56%.
- Worked on shifting a Web application from Monolithic to microservice architecture to improve performance by 40%.
- Added **Export to Excel** functionality to the application using Apache POI v5.2.3.

SKILLS

Technical Languages: Java 11 · JavaScript · HTML · CSS · Oracle SQL · C++ · Python

Frameworks: Spring Boot · Spring MVC · Hibernate · Rest APIs · Angular · Struts · Eh Cache

 ${\sf Tools: Postman \cdot Maven \cdot Docker \cdot Jenkins \cdot Git/Gerrit \cdot Jira \cdot CI/CD}$

Operating Systems: Linux · Windows

Education

Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology Bachelors of Engineering

Patiala, Punjab

06/2018 - 06/2022

• Secured a CGPA of 8.21 in Computer Engineering branch.

Shiksha Niketan Sr. Sec. School

Jammu

Senior Education

2018

• Achieved 88.2% in 12th / Intermediate PCM (non-medical) affiliated to State Board.

Projects

HRMS application

Developed of a robust HRMS portal featuring user management, leave application, and approval workflows. Utilized HTML/CSS/JS for a user-friendly interface and Spring Boot/PostgreSQL for a scalable backend. This project demonstrates full-stack development and data management.

Savior Eye (Capstone Project)

Developed assistive technology for the blind using **OpenCV, TensorFlow, and Raspberry Pi 5.** This project integrates hardware and software to create an impactful solution for visually impaired individuals. This device leverages computer vision and machine learning to:

- Detect user location via GPS and geospatial data.
- Recognize familiar faces through facial recognition with TensorFlow.